Hao Phung

① hao-pt.github.io | ② tienhaophung@gmail.com | ○ hao-pt | ③ Google Scholar

Research interests

My primary research interests lie in the field of Computer Vision, with a specific focus on deep generative models. Currently, I am actively engaged in improving the efficiency and controllability of diffusion models, particularly in their application to conditional image generation.

EDUCATION

Vietnam National University Ho Chi Minh City - University of Science
Bachelor of Computer Science; GPA: 8.40/10 (in-major GPA: 9.05/10); Rank: 14/320

Viet Nam

Aug 2016 - Nov 2020

PUBLICATIONS

(*) denotes equal contribution

- Quan Dao*, <u>Hao Phung</u>*, Binh Nguyen, Anh Tran, **Flow Matching in Latent Space**, arXiv preprint, 2023. [paper, code, page]
- Thanh Van Le*, <u>Hao Phung</u>*, Thuan Hoang Nguyen*, Quan Dao*, Ngoc Tran, Anh Tran, **Anti-DreamBooth:** Protecting users from personalized text-to-image synthesis, in *International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV)*, 2023. [paper, code, page]
- <u>Hao Phung</u>*, Quan Dao*, and Anh Tran, **Wavelet Diffusion Models are fast and scalable Image Generators**, in *Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR)*, 2023. [paper, code]
- H. Vo*, <u>T.H. Phung</u>*, and N. Ly, **VQASTO: Visual Question Answering System for Action Surveillance based on Task Ontology**, in *NAFOSTED Conference on Information and Computer Science (NICS)*, 2020. [paper]

EXPERIENCE

VinAI Research

Hanoi, Vietnam

Aug 2021 - now

- AI Research Resident Advised by Dr. Anh Tran

 Project: Flow Matching in Latent Space
 - * Introduce a latent flow matching framework that targets high-resolution image synthesis and various types of conditional image synthesis.
 - Project: Anti-DreamBooth: Protecting Users from Personalized Text-to-Image Synthesis (filed for a US patent)
 - * Introduce perturbation learning algorithms for enhanced user protection against malicious risks in personalized text-to-image synthesis.
 - Project: Wavelet Diffusion Models are fast and scalable Image Generators (filed for a US patent)
 - * Propose a wavelet-based diffusion scheme that accelerates image generation by leveraging low- and high-frequency components of wavelet subbands at the image and feature levels.

Applied Rotation Program - Led by Mr. Tin Trung Duong

Jul 2022 - Oct 2022

• Present a pipeline for Object Search using Open Vocabulary Object Detection that enables the retrieval of similar outputs based on a query object.

AI Engineering - Advised by Dr. Toan Duc Bui and Dr. Rang Nguyen

Dec 2020 - Aug 2021

- Investigated SOTA semi-supervised learning for Image Classification and Monocular 3D Object Detection.
- Validated and benchmarked AI models for Autopilot projects (e.g. Camera Degradation, Lane detection).

Skeleton-Based Abnormal Behavior Recognition

Ho Chi Minh, Vietnam

Research Collaborator - Led by Assoc. Prof. Ngoc Quoc Ly (cooperated with SNA Global)

Sep 2019 - Mar 2020

• Developed a real-time anomaly action recognition system by accelerating pose tracking and transforming skeleton sequences into spatio-temporal features for action classification using EfficientNet.

KMS Technology

AI Engineer Intern - Advised by Mr. Hoa Trong Vu

Ho Chi Minh, Vietnam Aug 2019 - Nov 2019

• Worked on an image matching problem for automated software testing by manually collecting and refining images, followed by fine-tuning a classification network on the curated dataset.

Professional activities

• Reviewer: ECCV (2024), SIGGRAPH (2024), TPAMI (2023)

Honours and Awards

• Outstanding thesis award

2021

• Top 5 IT students in academic year

2018 - 2019

PROGRAMMING SKILLS

• Languages: Python, C/C++, HTML/CSS, SQL.

• Technologies: PyTorch, Tensorflow, OpenCV, Scikit-learn, Git, LATEX, Docker, Linux.

LANGUAGES

• Vietnamese: Native

• English: IELTS Academic 7.0

 \bullet Cantonese: Beginner

EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

AI Day 2022

Panel speaker

Hanoi, Vietnam Aug 2022